So far so good.
Let the next argument which is the mark.
So because as you know I'm lazy.
I'm just going to do control the in here and out of this life for me.
And now I have to do is just change the options in here.
So the next option that I'm adding to my parser object is the option to allow the user to enter a new
MAC address.
So we're going to use dash M for D-Mark or they can do a dash dash.
Mark to give me the mark we're going to store this under Neumark and in the help we're going to say
new MAC address OK.
Just another option we added.
Exactly the same that we did the one before and because we're calling the parser that parse args we
don't really need to do anything more if we go down and run the help again.
You can see we have a new option which is Dash M or dash dash Mark and the help message for this is
it's the new MAC address that the person wants to use.
Now this is all good.
Now we're displaying the right help message.
We can accept user input using the arguments.
The only thing is we're still not able to use the values that the person enters.
So we're still not using it anywhere in the code and we don't even know how to use that.
Now let's have another look at our code.
So first we're creating an object that can handle user input using arguments then we're adding options
to this object.
And finally we're using a method or with this object that's called Par's args which basically allows
the object to understand what the user has entered and handle it.
And also returns the arguments and the values that the user entered to a variable.
If we actually give it a variable so it returns two sets of information it returns the arguments and
the values.
So for example let's say we were on Python might change your why.
And we said the interface to line zero.
And we said demarc 2 0 0 1 1 2 2 3 3 4 4 5 5.
In this case the arguments are interface and Mark and the values are Lan's 0 0 0 1 1 2 2 3 2 4 4 5 5.
So that's why when we call parser that parse args it's going to go through everything that the user
inputs in here and it all separated into two sets of information.
The first set is arguments which is interface and Mike.
And the second one is the values or options which is non-zero and the MAC address in here.
So to capture these two sets of information we have to use variables and to do that we're going to do
because we're using two variables in one line we're going to have to use two brackets and we're going
to say options arguments are equal to whatever parser does parse args will return to me.
So you can think of this as a function.
It's actually a method not a function.
And we'll talk about that in more details later on.
But what you need to understand is this method will return two sets of information the arguments and
the options and to capture this.
We're using two variables.
We're calling them options.
Arguments are equal to whatever this is going to return to me.
Now keep in mind all the names I'm using here parser options arguments on picking these names because
I want to you can literally use x y Zed if you wanted to.
But like I said it's good to use meaningful names because it makes programming easier and it makes our
code clearer.
So after this line the options variable is going to contain the values.
So it's actually going to contain lines 0 0 0 1 1 2 2 3 3 4 4 5 5.
And the arguments variable is going to contain the arguments.
So it's going to contain dash dash interface dash dash mark.
So by understanding this you probably know that we're actually not going to use the arguments variable
right now because we never really use the arguments within our code.
But what is useful to us is the options here because this is what contains the values that the user
inputs to access the value for the interface which is land zero.
All we have to do is do options that interface.
So it's whatever value that we use in the dust in here.
Same goes for the mac address if we want to access the value that the user set for the MAC address.
All we have to do is just do options Daut Neumark.
So again it's the value that we set and the dust in here.
So you can literally replace every utterance here of interface with options dot interface and every
utterance in here of Neumark with options dot Neumark or to make it easier and make our code more readable.
We can just do interface equals options that interface and new Mark equals options that new Neumark
and that's it we're done now since interface anew Mark are already being used in here.
There is nothing else we need to do.
Now let's go and run our code.
I've already typed my command so we're doing Python.
Mike changer.
We're giving it the interface which is land zero.
We're given a demarc which is this.
If we hear and.
You'll see the print statement is actually print in the right values for us and if we do ifconfig line
0 you'll see that my mac address got reset to the MAC address that we want here.
Now let's use the program using the shorter arguments using the dash and dash em so we can just do Python.
Change your.
Why.
And we can just do dush.
I like this.
And let's change the MAC address this time.
For 88 0 and do dash em said the Neumark hit enter again.
Print statement is working fine.
And if we do if config 88 0 you'll see that the MAC address changed to what we wanted to.
Now our program is actually pretty good.
It accepts user input views and arguments.
It displays a help message.
If the target person wants to and the person can set a mark and that interface through the command line
and it will executed and change the MAC for them.
Now in the future we're actually going to be using more modules more objects more arguments and everything.
I showed you so far as going to become clearer.